I didn't study English at all.
>> And now you're a professor at a major
university here.
>> And at Yahoo, I was promoted first to
four years. You don't have to speak
perfect English. People don't care who
you are. Just express it. My name is
Kyoung Han. I currently live in San
Jose, California. It'll be 26 years as
of next June.
>> I take it you like living in California
then?
>> Yeah. Whenever I come to San Francisco
Airport from Korea, I feel liberated.
No one cares about me. Second, weather
is so good.
>> Got to love that California weather.
What first brought you to California?
>> I majored in computer science back in
Korea and I got my bachelor and master
and I started my career at Samsung
Electronics as a Windows application
developer. And I stayed there for five
years and it was actually military
obligation and it was supposed to end
May 2000. So, I was looking for my next
move from summer of '99 and my classmate
from college, he went to Stanford for
master and he co-founded a company
called MySimon and he sold it to CNET at
$700 million and
then he started his second company and
that's when he offered me to join his
second startup.
>> Wow.
>> I didn't have any plan to live outside
of Korea at all. Because of that, I
didn't study English at all. So, when I
moved June 2000, I wasn't really ready
in terms of language.
>> Now your English is great. How did you
>> Yeah, I'm not so sure. Yeah, along the
way I made a lot of mistakes. I still
do.
>> That's part of learning.
>> Yeah. Yeah. [laughter]
>> Do you have any specific memory, like a
funny moment, one of those mistakes you
made?
>> Yeah, I have so many. A lot of them are
situational. It's not just the language,
it's a combination of language, culture,
and new situation you've never been to.
So, here in California, there are a lot
of drive-thru restaurants. One day, I
came to In-N-Out, and then they were
asking me a bunch of options. Actually,
they're not asking that many options.
Only option is onion. So, I wasn't
really ready. And then they were asking
whether I want grilled onion, chopped
onion. I just say yes, yes, yes, yes.
I developed drive-thru phobia
>> Uh-huh.
>> since then. But still, whenever I went
to In-N-Out or any drive-thru, I'm a
little bit nervous.
>> That's fair. It's really tricky with the
speaker, it's harder to hear, so many
options, like
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> even I get a little nervous sometimes.
How did you improve your English from
then until now?
>> I think first thing I realized is that
listening is far more important than
speaking.
>> Mhm.
>> Writing is always hard, but these days
with AI, it's not a big problem anymore.
But back then, I thought I need to
improve listening first. Otherwise, I
cannot understand what others are
saying, then you cannot react. So, I
spent a lot more time on improving my
listening. And back then, Friends was
very popular. So, I was listening to
Friends dictation, and then mirroring,
things like that. But if you don't know
the words or expression, your hearing is
not going to improve.
>> Mhm.
>> Or sometimes they pronounce so quickly,
like instead of out of, out of. And to
make things even worse, here so many
diverse ethnic groups, and especially as
a developer, you work with lots of
Chinese and Indian. Now I can understand
Chinese accent and Indian accent without
any problem.
>> Mhm.
>> But back then, it was one of the hardest
things. So, part of the improving
listening is actually learning more
words, expression, and basically exposed
to a lot of conversation, interacting
with more diverse group of people so
that you can get used to, and it's just
a matter of time.
>> It's really impressive to hear how you
first came here and going through a
drive-thru was difficult, and now you're
a professor at a major university here,
speaking in front of lots of students,
giving lectures. Would you say that your
confidence has really bloomed?
>> Yeah, so that's actually one thing I
developed. First, I was shy and I was
worried whether I'm conveying my idea,
especially in English. But over time, I
kind of developed more confidence, and
now I have thicker skin. So, if I don't
understand, just say repeat one more
time for me, and if I feel like they are
not understanding me, and I also repeat
what I'm trying to convey. So, in that
regard, uh over time with age, I became
more relaxed. That helped me. And
another thing is language is a mean to
communicate. So, if you can speak
perfect pronunciation, syntax,
>> it will be even better.
>> But more important thing is the tone,
manner, body language, your attitude,
all combined, you interact with other
people. That's something I learned. It
took a while, and that made me more
confident in terms of speaking English
and interacting with other people.
>> I love your perspective on that.
Language is to communicate. You don't
have to be perfect 100% of the time.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> If you can kind of get your message
across, then you did it. You're
successful. I actually heard that you
have a term aura English.
>> right?
>> Yes.
>> Can you explain that a little bit?
>> Yeah. So, whenever I talk to founders
back in Korea who wants to enter global
market, US market in particular, they
are concerned about two things. One,
visa, which is the hardest. Second is
the language. And many said, I cannot
speak good English, and I need to
convince like VC or potential customers,
and they need to talk to future talent
who might be their team members. And I
kept telling them, as long as you can
convey your vision, mission, and that's
what matters. In Silicon Valley,
two-thirds of the founders are not born
in America. It's a majority immigrant
community, and some of them speak very
good English. Some of them are not, but
I have seen non-native, not-so-great
English founders making big success. So,
here, how you can convey your vision,
mission is far more important than
speaking perfect English. So, I kept
telling them, you should have aura
English or speak with confidence. It can
be a little bit broken. That's totally
fine.
>> Mhm. I heard a funny story about your
daughter talking about your English. Is
that right?
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. She and I speak Korean and English
mixed when she was in high school. I
didn't know, but I was saying this
expression back in the days as in
plural, not singular. I think it kind of
bothered my daughter, so she told me
that, "Dad, I can understand what you're
saying, but back in the days is not
natural. Back in the day in singular is
more natural. It was a big shock.
Because I've been using that expression
over a decade. [clears throat] I mean,
no one correct me.
>> And your daughter called you out.
[laughter]
>> So, I told her that if you notice any
more such wrong expression, unnatural
expression, tell me so that I can
improve my English. And then she said,
"Then I have to interrupt you every
other sentence."
>> [laughter]
>> And we cannot have a proper
conversation.
>> No.
>> [laughter]
>> And she said, "That's totally okay, Dad.
You can convey your ideas. That's what
matters."
>> I love that. And going back to career
stuff, I guess. So, you said you worked
at Udemy, right? Can you talk a little
bit about that? Like Udemy and then also
what you're doing now?
>> In 2000, I moved to Silicon Valley and I
worked for web search a startup my
friend co-founded. The company was
acquired by another company, which was
Looksmart, which happens to be Soukja's
company in New York, right?
>> What a small world.
>> That is crazy.
>> So, I stayed there for 6 months. The
company declared that they're going to
let go entire search division. So, from
that on, I prepared a lot of interviews
and I joined Yahoo. It was February
2004. And at that time, I had our first
kid and I didn't have green card and I
didn't make much money in the first 4
years here. So, the situation weren't
that great.
>> Mhm.
>> But that made me be more hungry. So, at
Yahoo, I met great managers, co-workers,
and I was promoted first 4 years in a
row and I became a director of
engineering and I learned interviewing,
hiring, onboarding, giving feedback.
Then eventually after 7 years of stay at
Yahoo, I quit. It took some courage
because it was comfortable and salary
was good but the company wasn't doing
well. Google was beating Yahoo in every
sense. So eventually I left and I joined
another small startup but which couldn't
secure next round of funding. So the
company went bankrupt. So that's when I
decided to take a year break. A lot of
people ask me what kind of plans I had
when I took a year break. I didn't have
any plan. It was more like out of whim
at the moment decision which I don't
regret and turn out to be the best
decision in my career. It made me stop,
reflect and what direction I need to go
in the second half of my career. At the
time of my gap year, my number one goal
was finding my dream. I never had dream
until then. But just because you have
time doesn't mean you'll find a dream.
It's totally independent. But I realized
that as I was working for my former
co-workers companies as a part-time,
finding a place where you can make an
impact is far more important. You just
feel you are alive. So with that lesson,
uh second half of my career, I decided
only work for smaller companies,
startups. That was the main decision and
I joined a company called Parlay War and
then I joined Udemy. So that was 2014
and I stayed there for 4 years. And
since Udemy, I took another break. First
gap year or sabbatical, I was more
anxious, but second time I was really
eager to start because from the first
the lesson I learned that nothing bad
happened. So second break, I had a more
fun. I did whatever I wanted to do. So
now I teach at San Jose State at Applied
Data Intelligence master program and I
do angel investments, career coaching
for individuals and I've been writing
books as well. So recently I published a
book called Leadership Practice. I
didn't write it expressly for the sake
of publication. I've been
writing all the lessons I learned in the
past two decades. It became this thick
and then I summarize and then became a
book.
>> Wow, that is an incredible story. Kind
of took a different path in life, I
would say. You went from the bigger
companies to the smaller companies and
it all worked out for you and now you're
inspiring young minds and coaching other
people on how they can do the same
thing. So
that's really incredible. Can you talk a
little bit or maybe give advice about
leadership since that's what your book
is on?
>> Uh yeah, leadership is not a born
talent. It's more of a skill. Meaning
you have to practice. Along the way, you
are going to make mistakes. As long as
you don't repeat the same mistake over
and over, that's totally fine. If you
say I'm going to be a good leader in 6
months, you are going to fail.
And you are going to blame your talent,
not your persistence or consistency. So
one lesson, have a longer time horizon
and build a small habit which can
compound over time. I think that's
biggest lesson I realized after I become
over 50. When I was younger, I thought
strong motivation, but strong motivation
can go so far, right?
So, with a longer time horizon, be
composed, be consistent, and that will
compound, and you will have much larger
lasting success.
>> I feel like this can apply to learning a
language as well. A lot of people say,
"I want to be fluent in a month or 6
months." But, like you said, it's a long
journey.
>> Yeah, like 10 minutes or 30 minutes a
day over a few years, your language will
be so much better. In terms of English
at work, as a individual contributor,
your English is not that important. But,
once you become a manager, you have to
convey feedback. So, how you speak, what
words, expression you pick up are going
to be really important. So, that's when
I was really paid attention to a lot of
other good managers, how they speak like
during meetings or when they give
feedback to other people. Second thing
is that's when I started reading a lot
of books on business leadership, which I
had no interest at all. There is a two
books I highly recommend. One is Crucial
Conversations, which made me a better
person as a manager, co-worker, husband,
father, things like that. Second book is
a sister book of Crucial Conversations.
It's Crucial Confrontation.
So, this one is more from work
environment. As a manager, how you can
give feedback. So, those two book, one I
learned a lot, second there are a lot of
great English expressions. So, I wrote
them down, memorized, and whenever I
keep feedback, I rehearse with those
expressions.
>> I feel like I should read the Crucial
Confrontations book, actually.
>> [laughter]
>> I could probably use some help with
that.
Can you talk about some of the
differences you might have noticed
between working in Korea versus working
in the US?
>> Here in America, especially in Silicon
Valley, there are a lot of people with
big dreams. They are not shy in terms of
expressing what they want. Korean
people, in general, don't act like that.
So, if you want to be more successful
and recognized here, I think you have to
talk about your ambition, your dream.
Don't limit yourself. Don't be too
self-conscious. Just express it. So,
that would be number one thing. And
second thing, here it's more
individualistic. People don't care who
you are. So, I think here you can pursue
a dream without being conscious of what
others think of you. But in back in
Korea, it's more collectivism. So,
people care about others' opinion.
Instead of going your own way, people
wants to go with what others are going.
And that actually translate into working
hours as well. So, in Korea, a lot of
people, their definition of work-life
balance is when I'm in office, I work.
When I'm out of office, I don't work.
Office is becoming a boundary. But in
America, at least in my experience,
people are not really creating that type
of boundary.
>> Mhm.
>> Whenever you have some important work,
even outside of office, people can still
work. Or they always think about the
work. But at the same time, if your kid
is sick or you are sick, it's completely
okay to work from home or go home early
or report to work late. So, in general,
where you are during work hours don't
really matter. So, if you are motivated,
people don't care about number of hours
and people have a longer hours of work.
Another difference is here, the
compensation can dramatically different.
Back in Korea, just because you work
longer hours and achieve more doesn't
necessarily translate into a much better
compensation.
But here, there is a big difference.
>> Was it difficult for you at first to
adjust to the American work culture?
>> I didn't have much problem. I feel like
it suited me better. I don't like
drinking.
>> Uh-huh.
>> I mean, drinking for fun is okay, but
drinking for the sake of drinking, I I
didn't like that.
>> That's true. The hoesik culture. Do you
find that at the American companies
you've worked at, there's a lot of team
culture still? Like, you know, eating
together or drinking together or
>> Uh if there is a hoesik, then it's
mostly lunch time. And whenever there is
a like gathering, weekend, it'll be
family. Team members will bring their
family. It's more family oriented. But
sometimes I miss drinking beer on the
way [laughter] home.
There's no such thing here.
>> A lot of companies now are talking about
going global. Do you think it's
necessary or not?
>> Depending on domain you are aiming for,
Korean market might be big, but a lot of
times I don't think it's big enough. So,
if you are going to suffer as a founder,
you better suffer for bigger market,
bigger opportunity. So, that's a common
mistake a lot of Korean founders make,
which is in Korea is small, so if you
start smaller domain, you have to add a
lot of additional features so that you
can cover more horizon. But in America,
you don't have to do that. Small segment
is big enough. So, I think that's
probably the biggest mindset change. And
second similar thing is in Korea, there
are a lot of regulation. So, if you are
accustomed to regulation, you don't
think outside of box. And with that
mindset, in America, you might start too
small. So, I have seen founders who
avoided regulation in Korea and carved
out a business, and then when they moved
to America, they realized that there's
no such regulation. So, those are the
things you are not in America, you never
realize. So, I think whether you enter
global market or not, I highly recommend
come to America or go to Japan or any
other country and see what kind of
opportunities are there.
>> So, you told us about your book that was
recently released. Do you have any other
projects that you're working on now?
>> For now, I'll continue to work as a
adjunct professor at San Jose State.
Other than that, uh another sort of
potential project, which I hope to work
on, is writing a novel. It's sort of
converting leadership book I wrote into
some characters and plot, things like
that, so that people can relate better
and understand better. And maybe if that
goes well, convert it into cartoon or or
things like that.
>> I read so many novels, so I'll wait for
this. I'll I'll looking forward to this.
>> Again, uh thank you for inviting me and
it's an honor to be in this channel. And
for the subscriber or viewers of the
channel, you don't have to speak perfect
English. Just be persistent, consistent.
Time is the most important factor. As
long as you are consistent, it will
compound over time and your language
will be so much better. So, don't give
up. Continue to work, study, and I
highly recommend Kelly's book, which was
really great and which my wife really
liked.
>> Thank you so much. [applause] Thank you.
It was such a pleasure talking to you.
Thank you so much for sharing your
story. I learned a lot and I genuinely
enjoyed our conversation, so
>> Thank you.
>> was all mine.
If you want to learn more about
leadership, make sure to check out his
book. We will leave the link below in
the comments. Thank you so much for
watching and we will see you next time.
Bye.